这是二零零六年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试
英语科听力部分。
该部分。
分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案。
转涂到客观题答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
Hello, International Friends Club.
Can I help you?
Oh, hello. I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day, except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian,
Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试。
正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节。
听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完。
每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如：现在，你有。
五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容：
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案画在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，
所以你选择
项，并将。题画在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
How much are the tickets?
They're 15 pounds each, but student tickets are half price.
Could I have two student tickets please?
Excuse me, I just want to check the boarding gate for BA16 to London.
Is it gate 22?
Oh, it's just changed.
Gate 25, down that way on the right.
Thanks. Do you live very far from your school?
About 8 kilometers, but it doesn't seem that far.
There isn't much traffic along this road.
It's great to go by bike.
Now, can we get the computers before Wednesday?
Well, it depends.
If it's less than 10 kilometers, we can deliver them on Tuesday.
But if it's farther away, it'll be on Thursday.
Where's your office?
Just round the corner.
You can't wear that, John.
It's black. What's wrong with a black shirt?
Everybody has a black shirt.
It doesn't look like you're going to a party.
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
the Hello, may I speak to Mr.
三个选项中，选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话前，你将有时间
阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后。
各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答
第六和第七两个小题。
现在，你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
I'm sorry, he's out for lunch.
Would you like to leave a message?
Uh, what time do you expect him back?
Say, in half an hour.
Thank you. I'll try back later.
Hello, may I speak to Mr.
Brown? I'm sorry, he's out for lunch.
Would you like to leave a message?
Uh, what time do you expect him back?
Say, in half an hour.
Thank you. I'll try back later.
听下面一段对话。
回答第八和第九两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间。
阅读这两个小题。
Welcome to Youth Hotel.
Can I help you?
I'd like a room for the night.
Would you like a single room, a double room, or a room for three?
A single room, please.
Can I pay by check?
Sure. Fill in this form, please.
Need my student card number?
No, just your address and telephone number.
Okay, here is the form.
Very well. Here's your key to room 212.
Thank you. Have a good stay.
Welcome to Youth Hotel.
Can I help you?
I'd like a room for the night.
Would you like a single room, a double room, or a room for three?
A single room, please.
Can I pay by check?
Sure. Fill in this form, please.
Need my student card number?
No, just your address and telephone number.
Okay, here is the form.
Very well. Here's your key to room 212.
Thank you. Have a good stay.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十至第十二三个小题。
现在，你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
Hi, you must be that new secretary.
Welcome. I'm Tom Robinson from Public Relations.
Hi, Mr. Robinson.
Thanks. My name is Lisa Jones.
Working in sales now.
Please call me Tom, Lisa.
Okay. Tom, have you worked here long?
Yes, over 20 years.
Wow, that is a long time.
Do you enjoy working here?
yes. I suppose I took the job because, well, the money is good and it's a good place
to work in.
But to be honest, what I really enjoy is the chance to go abroad, just visiting
other countries. That's the best thing.
That's nice. For me, the best thing about working here is that I live close to the
office. I can go home for lunch and I don't have to worry about the traffic.
you must be that new secretary.
Welcome. I'm Tom Robinson from Public Relations.
Hi, Mr. Robinson.
Thanks. My name is Lisa Jones.
Working in sales now.
Please call me Tom, Lisa.
Okay. Tom, have you worked here long?
Yes, over 20 years.
Wow, that is a long time.
Do you enjoy working here?
Well, yes. I suppose I took the job because, well, the money is good and it's a good
place to work in.
But to be honest, what I really enjoy is the chance to go abroad, just visiting
other countries. That's the best thing.
That's nice. For me, the best thing about working here is that I live close to the
office. I can go home for lunch and I don't have to worry about the traffic.
Thank Now, Kathy, do we know when the visitors from India are coming?
听下面一段对话，回答
第十三至第十。
六四个小题。
现在，你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题
We offered them three choices, the end of March, the middle of April, and the
beginning of May.
And they chose the earliest one, which is good, actually, with the exams coming up
in May. Right.
And how many are coming?
Did you say about 12?
Yes, they said 12 at first, but changed to 10 this morning.
Good. We have eight weeks to prepare.
Here are my suggestions.
On the first day, a welcome party.
Then they can visit the schools in the district on the second and third days.
We've got to remember, this group wants to look at how computers are being used in
the classroom. Exactly.
So I want to ask Mr.
Goodman to give them a talk on this on the afternoon of the third day.
That'll fit in very nicely.
And on their last day, they want to do some sightseeing.
We could take them on a tour of London, but many of them may have been there
already. And Scotland will be too far away.
Why not take them for a walk along the coast?
It should be interesting.
Good idea, Kathy.
I'm sure they'll like it.
Now Kathy, do we know when the visitors from India are coming?
We offered them three choices, the end of March, the middle of April, and the
beginning of May.
And they chose the earliest one, which is good actually, with the exams coming up in
May. Right. And how many are coming?
Did you say about twelve?
Yes, they said twelve at first, but changed to ten this morning.
Good. We have eight weeks to prepare.
Here are my suggestions.
On the first day, a welcome party.
Then they can visit the schools in the district on the second and third days.
We've got to remember, this group wants to look at how computers are being used in
the classroom. Exactly.
So I want to ask Mr.
Goodman to give them a talk on this on the afternoon of the third day.
That'll fit in very nicely.
And on their last day, they want to do some sightseeing.
We could take them on a tour of London, but many of them may have been there
already. And Scotland will be too far away.
Why not take them for a walk along the coast?
It should be interesting.
Good idea, Cathy.
I'm sure they'll like it.
听下面一段对话，回答。
好，第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题
There are many interesting stories about how a baby learns to say its first word.
Now, Mark, would you like to share your story with us?
Okay, here's my story.
I was about 18 months old, I think, and I had just started saying my first word.
Every time a truck went by, I would shout a word that sounded like truck.
But to everyone else, it sounded nothing like it.
My parents tried to correct me, but failed.
Then, about three months later, we traveled to New York.
As we were waiting for our plane at the airport, I looked out of a huge window.
At that very moment, I saw the largest truck in the world.
I had to tell someone about this.
I turned to my father, who was standing next to about a thousand people waiting for
various flights, and screamed,
My father tried hard to shut me up, but I was so excited, I kept screaming my
special word. My poor mother decided she didn't know this baby, and ran into the
ladies' room, where she hid until I finally stopped.
Well, I learned how to say truck correctly, and soon I was talking like a normal
child. However, my parents will never forget the very first word I produced in my
life. There are many interesting stories about how a baby learns to say its first
word. Now, Mark, would you like to share your story with us?
Okay, here's my story.
I was about 18 months old, I think, and I had just started saying my first word.
Every time a truck went by, I would shout a word that sounded like truck.
But to everyone else, it sounded nothing like it.
My parents tried to correct me, but failed.
Then, about three months later, we traveled to New York.
As we were waiting for our plane at the airport, I looked out of a huge window.
At that very moment, I saw the largest truck in the world.
I had to tell someone about this.
I turned to my father, who was standing next to about a thousand people waiting for
various flights, and screamed,
Truck, My father tried hard to shut me up, but I was so excited, I kept screaming my
special word. My poor mother decided she didn't know this baby, and ran into the
ladies' room, where she hid until I finally stopped.
Well, I learned how to say truck correctly, and soon I was talking like a normal
child. However, my parents will never forget the very first word I produced in my
life. The
第二节。
到此结束。
现在，你有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案
转涂到客观题答题卡上